Guide to the Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter Records 1970-1997 AIS.2000.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter Records
1970-1997
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Sierra Club. Pennsylvania Chapter
AIS.2000.16
16.25 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
The Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter is an environmental organization which focuses on issues related to the state's environment, particularly the issues of nuclear power and waste disposal. Other environmental concerns the chapter addresses include strip mining, water quality, and wetlands conservation. This collection consists of materials related to the Pennsylvania chapter and the activities of the national Sierra Club organization. Memos, meeting minutes, correspondence, and other materials document the Sierra Club's local and national efforts. The materials date from the early 1970s through the late 1990s.
History
The Sierra Club is a national organization dedicated to using lawful means to protect the environment. The Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter focuses specifically on issues related to the environment of Pennsylvania, including nuclear power and waste disposal. The chapter was founded in 1972 through the consolidation of five other environmental groups. Official Sierra Club chapter status was granted on June 1, 1972, with the chapter divided into groups within the state by location. In addition to Allegheny County, there are groups in the Lehigh Valley, Bucks County, Kittatinny, and Moshannon, among other locations throughout Pennsylvania. The environmental issues initially considered by the chapter were strip mining, coal refuse disposal, and pesticides.
Today, the Pennsylvania chapter continues to concentrate its efforts on environmental issues including water quality, mining, and state public land use through a combination of grass roots efforts and conservation activities. The chapter remains organized in location-based groups throughout the state, all of which have members on the chapter's executive council.
Scope and Content Notes
These records document the activities of the Pennsylvania chapter and its efforts to lawfully protect the environment of Pennsylvania while also contributing to the national Sierra Club mission. While the Pennsylvania chapter is divided into ten groups, a majority of the records have come from the Allegheny and Southwestern groups. Memos, meeting minutes, correspondence, and other materials document the Sierra Club's local and national efforts.
The materials date from 1970 to 1997, although most concentrate on 1972 to 1991. The records have been arranged into four series pertaining to subject and format. Each series is more fully described in the series scope and content notes.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following four series:
Series I: Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter
Series II: National Sierra Club
Series III: Research Files
Series IV: Audio/Visual
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Sierra Club, Pennsylvania Chapter, conveyed through Dr. Sam Hays to the University of Pittsburgh in 1997 and February 2000.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Videotapes and cassettes within the collection require appropriate players in order to evaluate their content. A portion of the videotapes are broadcast videotapes.
Previous Citation
Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter Records, 1970-1997, AIS.2000.16, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Environmental Action Foundation Records, 1970-1996, AIS.1996.13, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Gail Rockwood Papers, 1964-2000, AIS.2000.20, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Wyona S. Coleman Papers, 1971-2005, AIS.2000.21, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Environmentalists; Environmentalism -- Pennsylvania; Environmentalism -- United States; Refuse and refuse disposal -- Pennsylvania; Hazardous wastes -- Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania; United States; Articles; Publications; Reports; Memorandums; Correspondence; Videotapes; Audiocassettes; Environment; Sierra Club. Pennsylvania Chapter. Southwestern Group; Sierra Club. Pennsylvania Chapter; Sierra Club. Pennsylvania Chapter. Allegheny Group
- Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter, 1972-1997; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I consists of correspondence, memos, reports, agendas, and meeting minutes related to the activities of the Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter. Subject files about specific issues are included, as are articles, correspondence, membership and activist lists, and a history of the chapter.
  The subject files in this series are related to the location of incinerators and landfills in Pennsylvania communities, and the efforts of the Pennsylvania chapter to stop their placement. Correspondence, memos, and meeting minutes detail other activities of the chapter throughout the late 1970s and early 1980s. Other materials detail the chapter's lobbying efforts to influence Pennsylvania politicians. A collection of newsletters detail community events in which the Pennsylvania chapter was active, including nature outings with inner-city children.
  Additional records document the activities of the Southwestern Group of the Pennsylvania chapter in the 1970s and early 1980s. These documents are mostly correspondence related to Sierra Club activities in response to a variety of environmental issues, especially strip mining. Newsletters produced by the Southwestern Group from 1972 to 1982 titled Southwestern News are included in this series.
  - History, Chapter Memos, and Meeting Minutes, 1.
    - PA Chapter History, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 1980 Agendas, January-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 1980 Agendas, July-December (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 1981 Agendas (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 1982 Agendas (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Chapter 1983 Agendas (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 1984 Agendas (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 1995-1996 Agendas (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Affiliations, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bulk Mailing Rates, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Chapter Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Environmental Education Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Questionnaire, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - International Committee (Pamphlet on the development of the tropics, released by the United Nations), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - PA Chapter National File (By-laws and memos on interests of the Sierra Club), 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Club Information, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chapter Policy Guides, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Legal Committee, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Pittsburgh Chapter Lobbyists, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lobbyist Candidates, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Membership (Local and National), 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Outings Policy, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Club Priorities (ranked by importance), 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - National News Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Chapter Directories, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - PA Chapter Brochures & Fundraising, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Insurance, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Special Newsletters, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - New Groups, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Responses to Local Environmental Concerns, 2.
    - Strasburg Landfill, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Radioactive Waste Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Heleva Landfill, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cherryville, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Various Clippings, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - CHRIN Landfill, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - York City Incinerator, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Lancaster Incinerator, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Centre County Solid Waste Management, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Berks City Incinerator, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Leigh Valley Incinerator, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Potter City Incinerator, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - York City Incinerator Permit (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Radioactive Waste- Canonsburg, PA, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Federal Coal Leasing, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Priority Campaigns (Pamphlets dedicated to the Sierra Club's Clean Water Campaign), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Chesapeake Bay, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Assisted State Issues, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Pine Creek, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Limerick Nuclear, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Department of Environmental Resources Probe, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous State Issues, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Oil and Gas (Bill copies and memos on House Bill #402, protecting residents from companies drilling for oil & gas on their property without their consent), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Project 70 Lands (court proceedings & memos dealing with the Project 70 land acquisition case in Schuylkill County over the building of a mall), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Raptor Conference (Dickinson College, Carlisle, PA), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Delaware River, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Conneaut, OH (US Steel Mill), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Inspection and Maintenance (I/M), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Lake Pleasant (Erie County, PA), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Montage (memos between the Sierra Club and Montage Inc., on the construction of a ski resort in Moosic, PA), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Chapter Activities: Outreach and Activism, 3.
    - Raptor Conference, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Tock's Island, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Trexler Dam, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Proposed Statewide Wilderness System, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - PA Legislation Lobbyists, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny National Forest, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Transportation, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC), 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Legal Activities, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Air- SIP, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Sierra Club Info, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - PennDOT 21st Century Focus Group Meeting, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Clean Air/ National Resources Defense Council, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Health Issues (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Low Level Energy, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Current Bills of Interest, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Conservation Subcommittees & Political Action Chairs, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Club Testimony (Testimony by various club members on a variety of environmental topics), 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Inner City Outings Newsletter, January 1978-August 1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - DER Environmental Economics Program, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - PA Energy Policy, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - PA Energy Parks, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Draft Audit Findings, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Department of Environmental Resources (DER), 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Anti-Smoking Legislation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Clean Air Act, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - PA Chapter Political Training (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - PA Chapter Lobby Campaign (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - PA Chapter Activist Reference List, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - PA Chapter Membership, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Sierra Club Radioactive Waste Campaign, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Strip Mining (Box 3, Folder 32-35)
    - Radioactive Waste- Canonsburg, PA (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Chapter Correspondence and Administrative Information, 4.
    - Sierra Club Reports, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Political & Environmental Events (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chapter Newsletters, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Political Committee (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Activist Network Serving Environmental Leaders (ANSEL) Worksheets, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Petition Campaign to Replace Watts, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Clean Air Strategies, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - State Parks, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Sierra Club Conservation Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Sierra Club Guides, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Sierra Club's Environmental Voter Education Campaign, 1991-1998 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Treasurer's Report & Budget, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Conflict Resolution Committee, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Utility Commission, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste Disposal in PA: Recommendations Procedures & Assessment, November 1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Sierra Club Environmental Lobby (SPEL), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - PA Chapter Newsletter, Sylvanian, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - PA Chapter Newsletter Inserts, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hazardous Waste Policy, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Wild Resource Conservation Fund, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence Concerning Interstate 99/Route 220, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Political Actions Fund, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Sierra Club Publication: Environmental Spotlight, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Chapter Publicity, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Sierra Club in the News (various clippings that pertain to the Sierra Club), 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
    - HB 1852, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - DER/ Citizen Interaction Committee, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Allegheny National Forest, 1974-1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Wyona Coleman, 1987-1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1979-1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Materials, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Materials, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Materials, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - By-laws and Regional Groups Handbooks, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Committee of Pennsylvania Environmental Groups (COPEG), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Materials, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - PA Chapter Meeting materials, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - PA Chapter Memorandums, 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Chapter and Group Newsletters, 5.
    - Miscellaneous PA Chapter Material, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence & Material, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - PA Chapter Memorandums & Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - PA Chapter Meeting Minutes, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Memorandum on Possible Litigation of State Mine Bond Program, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mining, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny Group Newsletters, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletters, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletters, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletters, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletters, 1972-1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletters, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletters, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - PA Chapter Newsletter, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Photos (photo negatives, cartoons, etc.) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletter, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Southwestern Group Newsletter, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- National Sierra Club Organization, 1970-1989; II.
  Series II consists of memos, correspondence, meeting minutes, newsletters, budgets, and policy guidelines for the national Sierra Club. Policies proposed by the Sierra Club and associated publications are included as well. The materials detail the efforts of the national Sierra Club organization to recruit and train volunteers and staff members. A majority of the documents consist of national news reports from the 1980s which provide an overview of Sierra Club efforts. Materials detailing the national policies and guidelines of the Sierra Club are present as well. The records date from 1970 to 1989. Materials related to this series' subject matter can be found in the videotapes in Series IV.
  - National News Report, Policy Information, and Publications, 1.
    - Energy Policy Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sierra Club Publications (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - National Publications, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR), June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Hitting Home": A report on the effect of Ronald Reagan's environmental policies on local communities, as reported by the National Resources Defense Council, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Presidential Profiles, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Proposed National Policies, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Media (memos and agendas on media plans & Public Service Announcements), 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - National News Reports (NNR), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - National News Reports (NNR), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - National News Reports (NNR), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - National News Reports (NNR), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Radioactive Waste Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Radioactive Waste Campaign, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - "Waste paper": Copies of the Sierra Club magazine on radioactive waste, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Reprinted Energy Articles, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - SELP Groups, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Energy Reports, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Grants, 1979-1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - National News Reports (NNR), 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Training for Effectiveness (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Sierra Club Journals, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Research Files, 1984-1991; III.
  Series III consists of a collection of newspaper clippings from local and national papers related to a variety of environmental issues including solid waste disposal, the Superfund hazardous waste clean up bill, and water pollution. Clippings from magazines and other publications are included and are arranged alphabetically. Most of the clippings are from the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette and The Patriot from Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. They range in date from 1984 to 1991.
  - A-G
    - Acid Rain (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Activist Groups (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Agriculture (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Air Pollution (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Air Quality, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Alaska Oil Spill (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Appalachian Trail (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Asbestos (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Ashland Oil Spill (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Billboard (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Bottle Bill (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Budget (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Chernobyl (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Chesapeake Bay (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
    - Clean Indoor Air Act, HB 259 (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
    - Coal, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Condoguinet Creek (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Dams (General) (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Department of Environmental Resources (DER) (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
    - Earth Day (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Endangered Species (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Energy (Non-nuclear), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29-32)
    - Environmental Concerns, National (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Environmental Education (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - EPA (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Explosive (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Federal Agencies (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Flooding (Box 7, Folder 38-39)
    - Food Additives (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
    - Forestry (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Francis Walter Dam (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
    - Fundraising (Box 7, Folder 45-46)
    - Gasoline Volatility (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Global Environmental Perspectives (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Government Agencies (Box 7, Folder 49-50)
    - Great Lakes (Box 7, Folder 51-52)
    - Greenhouse Effect (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Growth & Development Problems (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Green Peace (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Gypsy Moths (Box 7, Folder 56-57)
  - H-I
    - Harrisburg Dam (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Hazardous Waste (Box 8, Folder 3-13)
    - High Speed Rail (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
    - Human Health (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
    - I-78 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
    - Incineration (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Independent Regulatory Review Commission (IRRC) (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    - Industrial Air Pollution (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Interstate Transport (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - I-P
    - Incineration (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Incineration- Solid Waste (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - Insurance (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Landfills (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
    - Land Preservation (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Lead Poisoning (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Legal/Environmental Issues (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Lehigh Valley Groups (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Limerick Nuclear Power Plant (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Lobby Disclosure (articles on non-profit status for organizations) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Medical Waste (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Military Hazardous Waste (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Military Waste (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Mining & mine-related illnesses (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - National Parks, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Nuclear/NRC and Power (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
    - Nuclear, General (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Nuclear Power, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Ocean Pollution (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Oil and Gas (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Oil Spills (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Outings (canoe) (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Ozone (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Parks (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - PCB (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Peach Bottom Nuclear Power Facility (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Pennsylvania, General (environmental & ecological issues) (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - P-S
    - PennVest Water Program (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Pesticides (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Philadelphia Solid Waste (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Trash Problems, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Plastic, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Point Pleasant, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Political Process Issue, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
    - Pollution Sources (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Ponds (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Population Growth, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Product/Toxic Liability, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Public Utility Commission, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
    - Public Lands, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Publications-Environmental, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Radiation- Human Health (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Radiation Problems, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Radiation Waste Disposal (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Radon, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Rainforests (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Recycling, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
    - Right to Know (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Rivers/Canals, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Save the Earth, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Scenic Rivers, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Sewage, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Shoreham Nuclear Power Station, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Sinkholes, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Sludge, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Solid Waste (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Solid Waste Management (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Source Reduction (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Sportsmen's Issues/Wildlife, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - State Politics, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Superfund (Box 10, Folder 37-38)
  - T-Y
    - Technology/Environment, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Three Mile Island, 1985-1989 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - Trails and Rails, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Transportation, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Trexler Dam (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Tocks Island (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Toxic (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Toxic Chemicals/Waste, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Union Carbide, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)